Wheeler, Walter; Papers apap212
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Walter Wheeler Papers
1977-2005
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap212
2.66 cubic ft.
This collection documents gay and lesbian publications with a particular emphasis on the Capital Region and Upstate New York. Material from New York City and neighboring states is also included.
Administrative History
Walter Richard Wheeler III is an LGBTQ activist.
Scope and Contents
The publications range from professionally produced magazines to independently published zines. These publications are scheduled to be cataloged in Minerva, the University Libraries' online catalog. The collection also includes material often considered to be ephemeral such as handbills, flyers, advertising postcards, stickers, matchbooks, and other promotional material for various events and venues. Objects includes a condom packaged by the AIDS Council Project HOPE and a latex dental dam from the Women's Action Coalition both of which were used to promote safe sex.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection has no series, arranged chronologically.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by Walter Wheeler in 2005 December.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Human Sexuality and Gender Identity; Gay activists--Periodicals.; journals (periodicals); Wheeler, Walter
- ACT (Albany Civic Theater), 1996 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 1)
- A.L.Y.S.O.N., 1989 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 2)
- ASP (Albany Student Press), 2000-2001 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 3)
- Amfar-AIDS Research, 1998 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 4)
- A&U, 1991-1992 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 5)
- A&U, 1993; 1997 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 6)
- A&U, 1998; 2005 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 7)
- Bay Windows, 1986; 1997 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 8)
- Bay Window, 2005 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 9)
- Bi Notes, 1996-1997 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 10)
- Capital Pride, 2001; 2005 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 11)
- CDC (Centers for Disease Control), Undated (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 12)
- Center Happenings, 2005 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 13)
- Community, 1989-1991 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 14)
- Community, 1991 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 15)
- Community, 1992 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 16)
- Community, 1993 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 17)
- Community, 1994 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 18)
- Community, 1994 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 19)
- Community, 1995 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 20)
- Community, 1996 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 21)
- Community, 1996 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 22)
- CommUnity, 1997 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 23)
- CommUnity, 1997 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 24)
- CommUnity, 1997-1998 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 25)
- CommUnity, 1998 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 26)
- CommUnity, 1999 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 27)
- CommUnity, 2004-2006 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 28)
- Each of Us Inevitable, 1977-1989 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 29)
- Farm, Undated (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 30)
- The Fifty Column, 1993 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 31)
- Gay Community News, 1996 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 32)
- Gaynet, 1992 (Box 1 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 33)
- Gayzette, Greater Utica Lambda Foundation (GULF), 1991; 1994-1996 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 1)
- GLBT-New Englands largest newspaper, 2005 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 2)
- The Griot Press, 1996 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 3)
- Human Rights Campaign, 1997; 2000-2001 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 4)
- Hurricane Girl, 1998 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 5)
- Hx, 1990 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 6)
- In Our Own Voices, 2005 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 7)
- In the Life-The Lesbian & Gay Newspaper of the Hudson Valley & Tri-State Area, 1993-1994 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 8)
- In the Life -The Lesbian & Gay Newspaper of the Hudson Valley & Tri-State Area, 1995 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 9)
- In the Life - The Lesbian & Gay Newspaper of the Hudson Valley & Tri-State Area, 1996 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 10)
- In the Life - The Lesbian & Gay Newspaper of the Hudson Valley & Tri-State Area, 1996 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 11)
- In the Life - The Lesbian & Gay Newspaper of the Hudson Valley & Tri-State Area, 1997 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 12)
- In the Life - The Lesbian & Gay Newspaper of the Hudson Valley & Tri-State Area, 1997 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 13)
- In the Life - The Lesbian & Gay Newspaper of the Hudson Valley & Tri-State Area, 1998 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 14)
- In the Life - The Lesbian & Gay Newspaper of the Hudson Valley & Tri-State Area, 1998 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 15)
- Inside Out Hudson Valley, 2004-2005 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 16)
- Inside Out Hudson Valley, 2005 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 17)
- Lambda Rising News, 1994-1995 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 18)
- The Lesbian and Gay Pink Pages, Gay Pride Issue, 1992 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 19)
- Lesbians, Gays, and Bisexuals Newsweekly Au Courant, 1996 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 20)
- LGNY (Lesbian & Gays New York), 1997 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 21)
- Love and Rage, 1990 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 22)
- Men Talk, Twin Cities Mens Center, 1989 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 23)
- Metroland, 1995 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 24)
- Metroline, 1997 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 25)
- Metroline, 2005 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 26)
- Metropolitan Community Church of the Hudson Valley, 1999 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 27)
- Next, 1996; 1999 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 28)
- Northeast Magazine, 2005 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 29)
- One in Ten, 1995 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 30)
- Out & About, Undated (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 31)
- Out in the Mountains, 1998-1999 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 32)
- People First, Rensselar Polytechnic Institute, Undated (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 33)
- PFLAG Pole, 2001 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 34)
- The Pink Paper, 1997 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 35)
- Positive Images, 1992 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 36)
- PWAlive, Newsletter by, for, and about People affected by AIDS, 1989 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 37)
- QNortheast, 2005 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 38)
- Queer Ramblings, 2005 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 39)
- Sapphos Isle, 1992 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 40)
- To Avoid Suffocation, Gull, #1-4, Undated (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 41)
- Two Rivers, 1996 (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 42)
- Venus, Undated (Box 2 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 43)
- 1. Womens Building News, (Albany), 1994-1996 (Box 3 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 1)
- Womens Building News, 1998-1999 (Box 3 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 2)
- Flyers, Handbills, Postcards, and Related Material, 1985-2005 (Box 4 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 1)
- Stickers, 1985-1995 (Box 4 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 2)
- Womens Action Coalition, Latex Dam, 1985-1995 (Box 4 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 3)
- Inside Out Hudson Valley, Matchbook, 1995-2005 (Box 4 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 4)
- AIDS Council Project HOPE, Condom, 19954-2005 (Box 4 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 5)
- ACT-UP!, Posters, undated (Box 5 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 1)
- Our Town, 1997 (Box 5 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 2)
- The Source, 1993 (Box 5 (Walter Wheeler Papers), Folder 3)